Guide to the Richard Courant Papers MC 150
New York University Archives
- Series II: Files from the Office of Richard Courant
  - Subseries A: General Files
    - Convair Scientific Research Program (2 of 2), 1950-1956 (Box 36, Folder 2)
    - Cooper Union, 1967-1970 (Box 36, Folder 3)
    - Corcoran, Virginia, 1943 (Box 36, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence, 1935-1939 (Box 36, Folder 5)
      Includes correspondence to/from and about Albert Einstein, Norman Davidowitz, Science magazine and Hans Lewy
    - Correspondence, 1940-1944 (Box 36, Folder 6)
      Corresponence to/from and related to Spanish translation of Courant's work, the Army Specialized Training Reserve Program, S. Chandrasekhar, Norman Davids (Davidowitz), the U.S.S.R. Embassy and letters requesting feedback on What is Mathematics?
    - Correspondence, 1940-1944 (Box 36, Folder 7)
      Corresponendence to/from and about Norman Davids (Davidowitz), T. Freeman Cope (Queens College). This folder also includes letters from Albert Einstein and Felix Frankfurter
    - Correspondence, 1945 August-November (Box 36, Folder 8)
      Contains Memo Concerning An Institute for Research and Advanced Training in Mathematics and Mechanics at New York University and responses, corrresondence to/from Radio Corporation of America (RCA), Bell Telephone Labs and the OSRD
    - Correspondence--Personal, 1945-1947 (Box 36, Folder 9)
      Correspondents include Klaus Clusius, Courant's daughter Gertrude and Wilhelm Flügge
    - Correspondence, 1945 November-1949 December (Box 36, Folder 10)
      Contains memos and reports re: establishment of mathematics institute at NYU, other academic issues, corresondence with Ralph Flanders, Abraham Flexner, Harry Woodburn Chase
    - Correspondence, 1947-1955 (Box 36, Folder 11)
      Correspondents include Fritz Baade, David Bertin, Norman Davids and others
    - Correspondence, 1956-1958 (Box 36, Folder 12)
      Includes correspondence related to NYU and IMS
    - Correspondence, 1960-1964 (Box 37, Folder 1)
      Includes material from and about the American Mathematical Society, National Academy of Sciences and IBM
    - Correspondence, 1960-1964 (Box 37, Folder 2)
      Correspondence and work of A. Kyrala, correspondence related to "On Fermat's 'Last Theorem'" by Evaristo Suarez, misc.
    - Cosmos Club, 1953-1969 (Box 37, Folder 3)
    - Courant Institute of Mathematical Sciences, 1964-1968 (Box 37, Folder 4)
    - Courant Institute of Mathematical Sciences--Administrative Crisis, 1966 (Box 37, Folder 5)
    - Courant Institute of Mathematical Sciences--Industrial Contributions, 1958, 1967-1968 (Box 37, Folder 6)
    - Courant Institute of Mathematical Sciences--Math Conference March 21-23, 1966, 1965-1966 (Box 37, Folder 7)
    - Courant Institute of Mathematical Sciences--Naming of Institute, 1961-1962 (Box 37, Folder 8)
    - Curtis-Wright Corporation, 1945 (Box 37, Folder 9)
    - "D" Misc., 1944-1960 (Box 37, Folder 10)
    - Dallenbach, Walter, 1947 (Box 37, Folder 11)
    - Darmstadt, Technische Hochschule, 1955-1959 (Box 37, Folder 12)
    - Dartmouth Eye Institute, 1946-1947 (Box 37, Folder 13)
    - Davis, H. Chandler, 1954-1958 (Box 37, Folder 14)
    - de Hoffman, Frederic (See "General Atomic"), 1955-1960 (Box 37, Folder 15)
    - de Hoffman, Frederic (See "General Atomic"), 1961-1970 (Box 37, Folder 16)
    - Deferment, 1945-1946 (Box 37, Folder 17)
    - dePrima, Charles, 1946-1957 (Box 38, Folder 1)
    - dePrima, Charles, 1947-1949 (Box 38, Folder 2)
    - dePrima, Charles, 1961-1969 (Box 38, Folder 3)
    - Deuring, Max, 1946-1958 (Box 38, Folder 4)
    - Deutsche Akademie der Wissenschaften, 1965-1966 (Box 38, Folder 5)
    - Diary Notice--D.C. Spencer, 1945-1946 (Box 38, Folder 6)
    - Diedrich, Gunther, 1947-1953 (Box 38, Folder 7)
    - Differential Equations of Mathematical Physics, 1937-1938 (Box 38, Folder 8)
    - Differential & Integral Calculus--Fan mail, 1937-1960 (Box 38, Folder 9)
    - Distribution Lists, 1947 (Box 38, Folder 10)
    - Division 5, 1943 (Box 38, Folder 11)
    - Donsker, Monroe, 1966 (Box 38, Folder 12)
    - Douglas, Jesse, 1964-1966 (Box 38, Folder 13)
    - Douglis, Avron, 1957-1959 (Box 38, Folder 14)
    - Duff, George F.D., 1963 (Box 38, Folder 15)
    - Dunn, L.C., 1944 (Box 38, Folder 16)
    - Dusseldorf Conference, 1961 September (Box 38, Folder 17)
    - Dyson, Freeman J., 1956-1958 (Box 38, Folder 18)
    - "E" Misc., 1946-1959 (Box 38, Folder 19)
    - "E" Misc., 1961-1970 (Box 38, Folder 20)
    - Ebin, Alexander W.--Universal Mathematics, 1966 (Box 39, Folder 1)
    - Eckhard, Carl--The Steady Flow of a Heavy Inviscid Fluid of Constant Density, 1958 (Box 39, Folder 2)
    - Eckhart, Gottfried, 1954-1958 (Box 39, Folder 3)
    - Eckmann, B., 1951-1959 (Box 39, Folder 4)
    - Edelstein, Julius C.C., 1948-1949, undated (Box 39, Folder 5)
    - Education of Applied Mathematicians--University of Denver conference, 1966 (Box 39, Folder 6)
    - Ehrenpreis, Leon, 1966 (Box 39, Folder 7)
    - E.I. du Pont de Nemours & Co., 1953-1958 (Box 39, Folder 8)
    - Eilenberg--Topology, undated (Box 39, Folder 9)
    - Einstein, Albert, 1946-1949 (Box 39, Folder 10)
    - Eighth International Congress on Theoretical and Applied Mechanics, 1952 (Box 39, Folder 11)
    - Election to Academy of Sciences of the U.S.S.R., 1966 (Box 39, Folder 12)
    - Election to Academy of Sciences of the U.S.S.R.--letters of congratulations, 1966 (Box 39, Folder 13)
    - Elektronische Rechenmaschinen und Informationsverarbeitung, 1956 (Box 39, Folder 14)
    - Emergency Committee in Aid of Displaced Foreign Scholars, 1937-1943 (Box 39, Folder 15)
    - Emergency (National) Institute for Advanced Instruction in Basic and Applied Sciences--memos, undated (Box 39, Folder 16)
    - Engineering Foundation, 1947-1949 (Box 40, Folder 1)
    - Epstein, Paul F., 1939-1946 (Box 40, Folder 2)
    - Equipment--Forms and Instructions (Navy), 1946-1949 (Box 40, Folder 3)
    - Equipment--Navy Contract NOa(s)-7370, 1945-1948 (Box 40, Folder 4)
    - Equipment--Receipts, 1946-1948 (Box 40, Folder 5)
    - Equipment--Unfilled Requests (Navy), 1939-1946 (Box 40, Folder 6)
    - Esso Education Foundation, 1958 (Box 40, Folder 7)
    - Expenses--European Trip, 1952 (Box 40, Folder 8)
    - Evaluating Committee for Institute for Mathematics (NYU), 1945-1946 (Box 40, Folder 9)
    - Evaluating Committee for Institute for Mathematics and Mechanics (NYU), 1946 (Box 40, Folder 10)
    - Evans, Griffith C., 1939-1960 (Box 40, Folder 11)
    - Evans, Griffith C., 1939-1960 (Box 40, Folder 12)
    - Ewald, Paul, 1948-1949 (Box 40, Folder 13)
    - "F" Misc., 1939-1960 (Box 40, Folder 14)
    - "F" Misc., 1961-1971 (Box 40, Folder 15)
    - Faculty (Courant Institute of Mathematical Sciences), CIMS publications, 1962-1965 (Box 40, Folder 16)
    - Fan Mail, 1927-1929, 1949-1960 (Box 40, Folder 17)
    - Fan Mail, 1958-1960, undated (Box 40, Folder 18)
    - Fan Mail, 1961-1973 (Box 40, Folder 19)
    - Federation of American Scientists, 1951-1955 (Box 41, Folder 1)
    - Feller, Will, 1948-1955 (Box 41, Folder 2)
    - Fichera, Gaetano, 1952-1955 (Box 41, Folder 3)
    - Ficken, Fred A., 1951-1954 (Box 41, Folder 4)
    - Film--Mathematical Association of America, 1965-1967, undated (Box 41, Folder 5)
    - Film (R-5)--script, undated (Box 41, Folder 6)
    - Financial Needs--Institute of Mathematical Sciences, 1959 March 31 (Box 41, Folder 7)
    - Flanders, Donald A. (Folder 1 of 2), 1943-1958 (Box 41, Folder 8)
    - Flanders, Donald A. (Folder 2 of 2), 1943-1958 (Box 41, Folder 9)
    - Flanders, Sen. Ralph, 1937-1949 (Box 41, Folder 10)
    - Flanders, Sen. Ralph, 1946-1955 (Box 41, Folder 11)
    - Flexner, Abraham, 1936-1951 (Box 41, Folder 12)
    - Flexner, Abraham, 1951-1957 (Box 41, Folder 13)
    - Ford Foundation, 1950-1960 (Box 41, Folder 14)
    - Ford Foundation, 1960-1964 (Box 41, Folder 15)
    - Ford, Lester, 1939-1951 (Box 42, Folder 1)
    - Foreign Periodicals Lists, 1943-1944 (Box 42, Folder 2)
    - Foreign Periodicals Lists, 1944-1945 (Box 42, Folder 3)
    - Forms (travel, print shop, etc.), undated (Box 42, Folder 4)
    - Forsythe, George, 1954-1957 (Box 42, Folder 5)
    - Foster, Ronald M., 1946-1947 (Box 42, Folder 6)
    - Foundation of Integrated Education, 1952-1957, undated (Box 42, Folder 7)
    - Foundation of Integrated Education, 1952-1957, undated (Box 42, Folder 8)
    - Fraenkel, Abraham, 1945-1958 (Box 42, Folder 9)
    - Franck, James, 1939-1958 (Box 42, Folder 10)
    - Franck, James--memorial obituary, 1964-1966 (Box 42, Folder 11)
    - Frank, Phillip, 1937-1939 (Box 42, Folder 12)
    - Fraser, Ronald, 1947-1948 (Box 42, Folder 13)
    - Friedman, Bernard, 1937-1962 (Box 42, Folder 14)
    - Friedrichs, K.O., 1929-1971 (Box 42, Folder 15)
    - Friedrichs, K.O.--Heaviside Operational Calculus, 1944 (Box 42, Folder 16)
    - Friedrichs, K.O.--Special Topics in Analysis (Folder 1 of 2), 1953-1954 (Box 43, Folder 1)
    - Friedrichs, K.O.--Special Topics in Analysis (Folder 2 of 2), 1953-1954 (Box 43, Folder 2)
    - Friedrichs, K.O.--Negatives for Blueprints (oil prints), undated (Box 43, Folder 3)
    - Fry, Thornton C., 1953-1954 (Box 43, Folder 4)
    - Fubini, Eugene G., 1941-1949 (Box 43, Folder 5)
    - Fubini, Guido, 1939-1942 (Box 43, Folder 6)
    - Fucks, Wilhelm, 1961-1962 (Box 43, Folder 7)
    - Fueter, Rudolph--"Functions of a Hyper Complex Variable", 1948-1949 (Box 43, Folder 8)
    - Functional Equations in Probability, 1932 (Box 43, Folder 9)
    - "G" Misc. (1 of 3), 1942-1960 (Box 43, Folder 10)
    - "G" Misc. (2 of 3), 1942-1960 (Box 43, Folder 11)
    - "G" Misc. (3 of 3), 1942-1960 (Box 43, Folder 12)
    - "G" Misc., 1960-1971 (Box 43, Folder 13)
    - Gabrilovitch, Leonid E., 1944-1949, undated (Box 44, Folder 1)
    - Gallatin Award--Dec. 1967, 1967-1968 (Box 44, Folder 2)
    - Galleys, 1939-1940 (Box 44, Folder 3)
    - Gardner, Clifford, 1948, 1952, undated (Box 44, Folder 4)
    - Gardner, Trevor, 1955-1956 (Box 44, Folder 5)
    - Gardner, Trevor (letter to), 1955 August 26 (Box 44, Folder 6)
    - Gardner, Trevor, U.S. Air Force (Memorandum re: scientific manpower shortage), 1955 November 17 (Box 44, Folder 7)
    - Gassner, Bette Jane--Lectures, undated (Box 44, Folder 8)
      Original folder title contains the following date: 12/13/54
    - "Gauss and the Current Situation in the Exact Sciences", 1955 (Box 44, Folder 9)
    - "Gauss and the Current Situation in the Exact Sciences", 1955 (Box 44, Folder 10)
    - "Gauss und Die Gegenwaertige Situation Der Exakten Wissenschaften", 1955 (Box 44, Folder 11)
    - "Gauss und Die Gegenwaertige Situation Der Exakten Wissenschaften", 1955 (Box 44, Folder 12)
    - "K.F. Gauss and His Impact on the Development of Mathematical Sciences", 1958, 1965 (Box 44, Folder 13)
    - Die Linaren Gebilde (Box 45, Folder 1)
    - Gelfand, Israel M. (See "Russian Mathematicians"), 1962, undated (Box 45, Folder 2)
    - General Atomic, 1956-1960 (Box 45, Folder 3)
    - General Atomic, 1961 (Box 45, Folder 4)
    - General Atomic (See also "De Hoffman"), 1961-1972 (Box 45, Folder 5)
    - General Electric Company, 1945-1957 (Box 45, Folder 6)
    - General Statement: Brief history [of IMS]--J.J. Stoker, 1958 (Box 45, Folder 7)
    - Geometrie Der Gewebe von Wilhelm Blaschke and Gerrit Bol, 1938 (Box 45, Folder 8)
    - Geophysical Institute, NYU, 1958-1960 (Box 45, Folder 9)
    - German Scientists, 1946 (Box 45, Folder 10)
    - German Universities (needs for reform, etc.), 1933-1948, undated (Box 45, Folder 11)
    - Germany, 1935-1952 (Box 45, Folder 12)
    - "Germany, Report on Impressions of Scientific Work in Goettingen and Hamburg"--N. Artin and R. Courant, 1947 (Box 45, Folder 13)
    - "Germany, A Summary Report on Conditions of Science"--N. Artin and R. Courant, 1947 (Box 45, Folder 14)
    - Giddings, Horace A., 1950-1952 (Box 45, Folder 15)
    - Golay, Marcel J.E., 1950-1951 (Box 45, Folder 16)
    - Golden, William, 1964-1970, undated (Box 46, Folder 1)
    - Goldman, D.E., 1944 (Box 46, Folder 2)
    - Goldmark, Peter C. (Columbia Broadcasting System), 1953-1954 (Box 46, Folder 3)
    - Goldschmidt, Jakob, 1941-1954 (Box 46, Folder 4)
    - Goldstein, Sidney, 1946-1950 (Box 46, Folder 5)
    - Goldstine, Herman H., 1947-1959 (Box 46, Folder 6)
    - Goldstine, Herman H., 1961-1964 (Box 46, Folder 7)
    - Gomory, Ralph (See also "IBM," "Piore"), 1966-1969, undated (Box 46, Folder 8)
    - Gortler, H., 1950-1955 (Box 46, Folder 9)
    - Göttingen, University of, 1946-1960, undated (Box 46, Folder 10)
    - Göttingen, University of, 1961-1962, 1970-1971 (Box 46, Folder 11)
    - Göttingen, University of--Wilhelm Weber, undated (Box 46, Folder 12)
    - Governing Council, NYU, 1962 November-1965 November (Box 46, Folder 13)
    - Governing Council, NYU (misc.), 1968 (Box 46, Folder 14)
    - Grad, Arthur, 1943-1960 (Box 46, Folder 15)
    - Grad, Arthur, 1961-1962 (Box 46, Folder 16)
    - Grad, Harold, 1950-1957 (Box 46, Folder 17)
    - Grad, Harold, 1960, 1962-1966 (Box 46, Folder 18)
    - Grammel, Richard, 1938-1959 (Box 47, Folder 1)
    - Graves, Lawrence, 1938-1951 (Box 47, Folder 2)
    - Greenberg, Herbert J., 1959-1960, undated (Box 47, Folder 3)
    - Greenberg, Herbert J., 1961-1965, undated (Box 47, Folder 4)
    - Greenwood, Thomas, 1941-1944 (Box 47, Folder 5)
    - Grenoble--Laboratoire Dauphinois D'Hydraulique, 1951-1954 (Box 47, Folder 6)
    - Griffin, Frank L., 1949-1950 (Box 47, Folder 7)
    - Griffin, Harriet--"The Concepts of the Theory of Numbers", 1949 (Box 47, Folder 8)
    - Group Health, 1945 (Box 47, Folder 9)
    - Grumman Aircraft Engineering Corp., 1953-1958 (Box 47, Folder 10)
    - von Grumpenberg, Herta List, 1938-1947 (Box 47, Folder 11)
    - Grunebaum, Ludwig H., 1945-1955 (Box 47, Folder 12)
    - Grunsky, H., 1949-1951 (Box 47, Folder 13)
    - Gundolf, Elizabeth, 1938 (Box 47, Folder 14)
    - Gutmann, Franz, 1939-1948 (Box 47, Folder 15)
    - "H" Misc., 1933-1960 (Box 47, Folder 16)
    - "H" Misc., 1960-1971 (Box 47, Folder 17)
    - "H" Misc., undated (Box 47, Folder 18)
      Contains copy of "Chapter VII," Methods of Mathematical Physics Vol. 2
    - Hadamard, Jacques, 1942-1943, undated (Box 47, Folder 19)
    - Hahn, Otto, 1947-1956 (Box 48, Folder 1)
    - Hahn, Otto--Certification of Original Painting by Herr Schoepp, 1970 (Box 48, Folder 2)
    - Hammer, Carl, 1939-1951 (Box 48, Folder 3)
    - Harrison, Marvin George, 1941-1944 (Box 48, Folder 4)
    - Hartshorne, E.Y., 1946 (Box 48, Folder 5)
    - Harvard University Computation Lab, 1946-1948 (Box 48, Folder 6)
    - Heald, Henry T., 1952-1960 (Box 48, Folder 7)
    - Hecke, Erich, 1946-1947 (Box 48, Folder 8)
    - Hedlund, Gustav A., 1949-1950, 1959 (Box 48, Folder 9)
    - Hedrick, E.R., 1937-1940 (Box 48, Folder 10)
    - Heineman Foundation, 1946-1959 (Box 48, Folder 11)
    - Heineman Foundation, 1947-1952 (Box 48, Folder 12)
    - Heineman Foundation, 1953-1955 (Box 48, Folder 13)
    - Heineman Foundation, 1961-1968 (Box 48, Folder 14)
    - Heineman Foundation Stationary, undated (Box 48, Folder 15)
    - Heisenberg, Werner, 1951-1957 (Box 48, Folder 16)
    - Hellinger, Ernst and Hanna, 1938-1947 (Box 48, Folder 17)
    - Hellmann, Reinhard K., 1937-1938 (Box 48, Folder 18)
    - Hellwig, Gunter, 1954-1956 (Box 48, Folder 19)
    - Hellwig, Gunter, 1961-1966 (Box 48, Folder 20)
    - Henrici, Peter, 1962 (Box 49, Folder 1)
    - Hersfeld, Karl F., 1939-1953 (Box 49, Folder 2)
    - Hertzig, Morris, 1939 (Box 49, Folder 3)
    - Herzberger, Max, 1938-1943 (Box 49, Folder 4)
    - Hester, James, 1961-1968 (Box 49, Folder 5)
    - "Hilbert als Analytiker und als wissenschaftliche Personlichkeit", undated (Box 49, Folder 6)
    - "Hilbert as an Analyst and Personality in Science", 1962 January (Box 49, Folder 7)
    - Hirschland Family, 1935-1957 (Box 49, Folder 8)
    - Hirzebruch, F., 1956-1957 (Box 49, Folder 9)
    - Hiss, Alger, 1948-1951 (Box 49, Folder 10)
    - Hildebrandt, E.H.C., 1939-1941 (Box 49, Folder 11)
    - Hildebrandt, Stefan, 1963-1971 (Box 49, Folder 12)
    - Hildebrandt, T.H., 1939-1947 (Box 49, Folder 13)
    - Hille, Einar, 1940-1948 undated (Box 49, Folder 14)
    - Hirsch, Caesar, 1939 (Box 49, Folder 15)
    - Hirschfelder, Joseph O., 1947-1953 (Box 49, Folder 16)
    - Hoerlin, Herman and Kate, 1954-1958 (Box 49, Folder 17)
    - Honorary Awards, 1949-1958 (Box 49, Folder 18)
    - Honorary Sc.D., Adelphi University, 1965-1966 (Box 49, Folder 19)
    - Hopf, Eberhard, 1945-1959 (Box 49, Folder 20)
    - Hopf, Eberhard, 1947-1961 (Box 49, Folder 21)
    - Hopf, Heinz, 1938-1945 (Box 49, Folder 22)
    - Hopf, Heinz, 1946-1947 (Box 49, Folder 23)
    - Hopf, Heinz, 1947-1968 (Box 49, Folder 24)
    - Hornig, Donald T., 1963 (Box 49, Folder 25)
    - Houtermans, Elsa, 1940-1957 (Box 49, Folder 26)
    - Hudson, George, 1938-1956 (Box 49, Folder 27)
    - Hudson, George, 1945-1950 (Box 49, Folder 28)
    - Hugh Cooper Corp., 1947 (Box 49, Folder 29)
    - Hughes Research and Development Laboratories, 1952-1954 (Box 50, Folder 1)
    - Hula, Erich, 1938-1939 (Box 50, Folder 2)
    - Hurewicz, W., 1943-1944 (Box 50, Folder 3)
    - "Hurwitz-Courant"--Helmut Rohr, 1959-1963 (Box 50, Folder 4)
    - "I" Misc., 1946-1947 (Box 50, Folder 5)
    - "I" Misc., 1951-1969 (Box 50, Folder 6)
    - IBM, 1962-1968 (Box 50, Folder 7)
    - IBM, 1968-1972 (Box 50, Folder 8)
    - IBM--Concerning Pressures on IBM from ALGOL Groups in Europe, 1962 (Box 50, Folder 9)
    - IBM--Endicott, NY, 1960-1968 (Box 50, Folder 10)
    - IBM--New York, NY, 1953-1959 (Box 50, Folder 11)
    - IBM--New York, NY, 1962-1963 (Box 50, Folder 12)
    - IBM--Oswego, NY, 1960 (Box 50, Folder 13)
    - IBM--Sweden, 1962 (Box 50, Folder 14)
    - IBM--Yorktown Heights, NY, 1960 (Box 50, Folder 15)
    - IBM--Yorktown Heights, NY, 1961-1966 (Box 50, Folder 16)
    - IBM--Zurich, 1957-1959 (Box 50, Folder 17)
    - IBM--Zurich, 1961, 1967, undated (Box 50, Folder 18)
    - Illinois Institute of Technology, 1951-1956 (Box 50, Folder 19)
    - Illinois Institute of Technology Honors Convocation, 1965-1968 (Box 50, Folder 20)
    - Indiana University, 1954-1959 (Box 50, Folder 21)
    - Index [Courant-Hilbert II] (1 of 4), 1961-1962 (Box 50, Folder 22)
    - Index [Courant-Hilbert II] (2 of 4), 1961-1962 (Box 50, Folder 23)
    - Index [Courant-Hilbert II] (3 of 4), 1961-1962 (Box 51, Folder 1)
    - Index [Courant-Hilbert II] (4 of 4), 1961-1962 (Box 51, Folder 2)
    - Institute for Advanced Study--Europe Inc., 1946-1947 (Box 51, Folder 3)
    - Institute for Basic Sciences, Memo Concerning, 1951 May 22 (Box 51, Folder 4)
    - Institute for Mathematics and Mechanics at NYU, Memo Concerning, 1951 June 8 (Box 51, Folder 5)
    - Institute for Mathematics and Mechanics at NYU, Memo Concerning, 1952 February 4 (Box 51, Folder 6)
    - Institute for Mathematical Sciences (IMS)--Administration--Budget and Finances, 1958, undated (Box 51, Folder 7)
    - Institute for Mathematical Sciences (IMS)--Advisory Board Correspondence, 1949-1959 (Box 51, Folder 8)
    - Institute for Mathematical Sciences (IMS)--Advisory Board Meetings, 1953-1958, undated (Box 51, Folder 9)
    - Institute for Mathematical Sciences (IMS)--Dedication, 1954 (Box 51, Folder 10)
    - Institute for Mathematical Sciences (IMS)--Dedication Ceremony, Correspondence Concerning (1 of 3), 1954 (Box 51, Folder 11)
    - Institute for Mathematical Sciences (IMS)--Dedication Ceremony, Correspondence Concerning (2 of 3), 1954 (Box 51, Folder 12)
    - Institute for Mathematical Sciences (IMS)--Dedication Ceremony, Correspondence Concerning (3 of 3), 1954 (Box 51, Folder 13)
    - Institute for Mathematical Sciences (IMS)--Development (including Ford Foundation), 1945-1958 (Box 51, Folder 14)
    - Institute for Mathematical Sciences (IMS)--Development (including Ford, Sloan foundations), 1959-1960 (Box 52, Folder 1)
    - Institute for Mathematical Sciences (IMS)--Formulation of Some Problems Facing IMS, NYU, 1958 (Box 52, Folder 2)
    - Institute for Mathematical Sciences (IMS)--History, 1952, 1972-1973 (Box 52, Folder 3)
    - Institute for Mathematical Sciences (IMS)--Memoranda re:, 1952 April 15 (Box 52, Folder 4)
    - Institute for Mathematical Sciences (IMS)--Memoranda re:, 1956 April 9 (Box 52, Folder 5)
    - Institute for Mathematical Sciences (IMS)--Memoranda A: Objectives of NYU IMS, 1952 December 15 (Box 52, Folder 6)
    - Institute for Mathematical Sciences (IMS)--Pamphlet Response, 1952-1955 (Box 52, Folder 7)
    - Institute for Mathematical Sciences (IMS)--Relationship between IMS and NYU Central Administration, 1959 (Box 52, Folder 8)
    - Institute for Research and Advanced Training in Mathematics and Mechanics, Memo Concerning, 1945, 1953, 1959 (Box 52, Folder 9)
    - "Integration in the Complex Domain"--Chapters 3 and 4, undated (Box 52, Folder 10)
    - Integrative Concepts in Science, Philosphy, Education 1951-1952 (Supplementary Readings), undated (Box 52, Folder 11)
    - International Congress of Mathematicians--Amsterdam, 1954 (Box 52, Folder 12)
    - International Congress of Mathematicians--Cambridge, 1950--Address (Box 53, Folder 1)
    - International Congress of Mathematicians--Cambridge, 1950 (Box 53, Folder 2)
    - International Congress of Mathematicians--Cambridge, 1950--from Von Neumann, 1949-1950 (Box 53, Folder 3)
    - International Congress of Mathematicians--Cambridge, 1950--from Von Neumann, 1949-1950 (Box 53, Folder 4)
    - International Congress of Mathematicians--Moscow, 1966 (Box 53, Folder 5)
    - International Congress of Mathematicians--Stockholm, Aug. 1962 (Box 53, Folder 6)
    - International Congress of Mathematicians--from J.J. Stoker, 1949-1951 (Box 53, Folder 7)
    - International Mathematical Union, 1952-1959 (Box 53, Folder 8)
    - Interscience Publishers Inc., 1937-1950 (Box 53, Folder 9)
    - Interscience Publishers Inc., 1940-1948 (Box 53, Folder 10)
    - Interscience Publishers Inc., 1951-1959 (Box 53, Folder 11)
    - Interscience Publishers Inc., 1960-1962 (Box 53, Folder 12)
    - Interscience Publishers Inc. Enclosure Slips, 1961-1962 (Box 53, Folder 13)
    - Introduction and Fundamental Concepts (Lecture Notes) 1 of 2, undated (Box 54, Folder 1)
    - Introduction and Fundamental Concepts (Lecture Notes) 2 of 2, undated (Box 54, Folder 2)
    - Introduction to Mathematical Analysis, 1951-1952, undated (Box 54, Folder 3)
    - Invitations--Misc. (1 of 2), 1946-1967 (Box 54, Folder 4)
    - Invitations--Misc. (2 of 2), 1946-1967 (Box 54, Folder 5)
    - Inyoken, California, 1945-1949 (Box 54, Folder 6)
    - "J" Misc., 1946-1969 (Box 54, Folder 7)
    - Jackson, Sen. Henry M. (NATO Committee) (1 of 2), 1957-1960 (Box 54, Folder 8)
    - Jackson, Sen. Henry M. (NATO Committee) (2 of 2), 1957-1960 (Box 54, Folder 9)
    - Jager, Willi, 1969-1971 (Box 54, Folder 10)
    - Janke, Liselotte, 1956-1958 (Box 54, Folder 11)
    - Japan, 1969 January-July (Box 54, Folder 12)
    - Jeans, J.H., "On the Equilibrium of Rotating Liquid Cylinders", 1951 (Box 55, Folder 1)
    - Jessen, Borge, 1949-1959 (Box 55, Folder 2)
    - Jet Propulsion Clippings, 1944 (Box 55, Folder 3)
    - Jewett, Frank B. Fellowships, 1947-1948 (Box 55, Folder 4)
    - John, Fritz, 1950-1967 (Box 55, Folder 5)
    - John, Fritz, 1951-1955 (Box 55, Folder 6)
    - John, Fritz (1 of 3), 1984-1986, 1994, undated (Box 55, Folder 7)
    - John, Fritz (2 of 3), 1984-1986, 1994, undated (Box 55, Folder 8)
    - John, Fritz (3 of 3), 1984-1986, 1994, undated (Box 55, Folder 9)
      Contains paper, "Existence for Large Times of Strict Solutions of Nonlinear Wave Equations in Three Space Dimensions for Small Initial Data."
    - John, Fritz--"Wave Propagation", 1950 (Box 55, Folder 10)